ISAIAH FRANCOIS

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

- francoiscoding.netlify.app/
- **** 3529893703
- **♀** Clermont, Fl
- in francoiscoding
- FrancoisCoding

A software development and performance engineering expert with 4+ years of experience in developing quality assured applications. A collaborative developer and engineer with experience and education in the hardware and software sides of technology who thrives on discovery and accelerating performance.

Skills

PROGRAMMING TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

Python

ReactJS

Express

Git

SQL Redux

SASS

MongoDB

Firebase

Cypress Testing

Typescript

web3.js

NextJS

ethers.js

Docker

Netlify Vercel

TailwindCSS

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Adaptability

Technical Troubleshooting and Debugging

Software and Engineering Documentation

Systems Architecture and Operations

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Performance Engineering and Measurement

Employment

Lead Front-end Developer

SpeechifAl

Remote Feb. 2021 to Current, Feb. 2021 to Current

SpeechifAI is the digital campaign suite for word-of-mouth marketing with ~\$300k in annual revenues and investments

- Built, iterated, and maintained interactive web pages, editable landing pages, and unique user experiences. Driving daily user engagement from ~600 5000 recurring users.
- Leveraged in-house APIs (REST) to build dynamic, interactive pages.
- Worked with Marketing UI/UX designers to translate designs into pixel perfect code.
- Be the expert on viability and approach to web projects.
- Defined and estimated work effort and duration.
- Grew technical knowledge by researching the latest development methods and techniques, sharing that information with the team and created development plans for them to grow within in their current realm.
- Developed new features to ensure the client needs were met, deadlines are achieved, and users have a seamless experience. This increased monthly recurring revenue **283.436%** and **3x** paying clients.

Bloom Institute of Technology Team Lead

Remote Oct. 2019 to July 2020

• Mentored 10+ students on how to learn effectively and solve programming problems.

- Provided daily feedback and issue resolution of all curriculum through Slack interface.
- Led daily standup meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate sharing of ideas and work progress, and provide guidance for that week's study material.
- Delivered one-on-one feedback and code review on a weekly basis, giving feedback on areas of improvement.

Projects

DevChat

Solo full-stack chat application allowing users to chat in real-time and video call any user across the platform. Firebase| React.JS | Semantic UI | Redux | Moment

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can have conversations and video call.
- Utilized the Jutsu Video API in order to establish video connections between users

React Movies

Solo IMDB style Web Application that provides up to date movie information and details. ReactJS | Bootstrap

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view information on over 10,000 of the latest movies released.
- Utilized The Movie Database API in order to display all information about latest movie titles to users.

Beach Resort

E-commerce application featuring a hotel where users can view featured rooms, filter through rooms, receive updated room information and book rooms through PayPal

React.JS | Contentful | Redux | PayPal

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a e-commerce platform where users can book a room at a virtual hotel.
- Utilized the Contentful CMS to create database to store rooms and the PayPal API to initialize user purchasing

Education

Bloom Institute of Technology · May 2019 to Feb. 2020 Full Stack Web Development

Remote